Paul Capra Papers
© 2004 University of Connecticut
Paul Capra Papers.
undated, 1966-1975.
Archives & Special Collections at the Thomas J. Dodd Research Center.
Capra, Paul.
2.5 linear feet.
Paul Capra was born 11 May 1939. He studied at Yale University (1961), Oxford University and Southern Connecticut State College. He received a Master's degree in Education research. Capra ran twice as the Republican candidate for mayor for the city of New Haven (1969, 1971).
MSS19770001
Biography
Paul Capra was born 11 May 1939. He studied at Yale University (1961), Oxford University and Southern Connecticut State College. He received a Master's degree in Education research.
In addition to holding positions in many community organizations, Capra was Assistant Director of Admissions for Systems and Research at Yale University form 1965 until 1970. He received the Distinguished Service Award from the New Haven Jaycees on 23 January 1970.
Capra ran twice as the Republican candidate for mayor for the city of New Haven (1969, 1971). In 1969, after receiving the GOP nomination, Capra was narrowly defeated by the Democratic candidate, Bartholomew F. Guida in New Haven's closest mayoral race in 18 years. Two years later, Capra ran again on the Republican ticket but Guida was re-elected by a wide margin. Capra dropped out of New Haven politics and accepted the position of Director of Development at the University of Connecticut.
Scope and Content
The collection includes correspondence, publications, newspaper clippings, photographs and scrapbooks pertaining to Capra's political career.
Arrangement
Series I: Campaign Papers, ( 1966-1975 )
Series II: Photographs, ( undated )
Series III: Scrapbook, ( 1971 )
Related Material
Archives & Special Collections has a substantial collection of political materials relevant to Connecticut. For detailed information on these collections please contact the curator or ask at the reference desk.
Index Terms
This record series is indexed under the following controlled access subject terms.
Subjects:
Document Types:
Correspondence.; Reports.; Financial Records.
Occupations:
Administrator.
Restrictions on Access
There are no access restrictions on this collection.
Acquisition Information
The collection was donated by Mr. Capra to the University of Connecticut Libraries in 1977. Until August 1979, the papers were maintained by the Special Collections Department. In 1979, they were transferred to the Historical Manuscripts and Archives Division. In 1995, the two departments were merged to create Archives and Special Collections which is now located at the Thomas J. Dodd Research Center.
Detailed Description
- Series I: Campaign Papers, 1966-1975
  - Campaign funds, undated (Box 1:, Folder 1)
  - Capra profile, undated (Box 2:, Folder 2)
  - Newspaper clippings, 1968-1969 (Box 2:, Folder 3)
  - Newspaper clippings, 1969-1974 (Box 2:, Folder 4)
  - Newspaper clippings
    - Primary election results, 1969 (Box 2:, Folder 5)
    - Election results, 1971 (Box 2:, Folder 6)
    - Election results, 1973-1975 (Box 2:, Folder 7)
  - Correspondence, 1969-1970 (Box 2:, Folder 8)
  - Correspondence, 1971-1972 (Box 2:, Folder 9)
  - Correspondence—R. M. Nixon, 1969 (Box 2:, Folder 10)
  - The Crow, 1969-1970 (Box 2:, Folder 11)
  - Distinguished Service Award, 1970 (Box 2:, Folder 12)
  - Editorial, 1971 (Box 2:, Folder 13)
  - Election results, undated (Box 2:, Folder 14)
  - GACETA, 1970-1971 (Box 2:, Folder 15)
  - Guest Book, 1971 (Box 2:, Folder 16)
  - Guest Book, undated (Box 2:, Folder 17)
  - The Hill Voice, 1971 (Box 2:, Folder 18)
  - Information and Referral Services, undated (Box 2:, Folder 19)
  - Modern Times, 1971 (Box 2:, Folder 20)
  - NAP Public Relations, undated (Box 2:, Folder 21)
  - New Haven Republicans, 1971 (Box 2:, Folder 22-23)
  - New Haven Republicans, 1971 (Box 3:, Folder 24-26)
  - The New Haven Star, 1971 (Box 3:, Folder 27)
  - New release copies (for Sparrow), 1971 (Box 3:, Folder 28)
  - New release copies (for Sparrow), 1971 (Box 4:, Folder 29)
  - Platform, 1966-1970 (Box 4:, Folder 30)
  - Weekly schedules, 1971 (Box 4:, Folder 31)
  - Scope, 1971 (Box 4:, Folder 32)
  - Speeches, undated (Box 4:, Folder 33)
  - Statistics notebook, undated (Box 4:, Folder 34)
- Series II: Photographs, undated
  - Photographs from campaign for mayor of New Haven (Box 5)
  - Solo portraits
  - Family photographs
  - Negatives
  - Album from campaign
- Series III: Scrapbook, 1971
  - Scrapbook from mayoral campaign, 1971 (Box 6)